Brother, I always tell you the same thing
that whenever you invest money in the market, whether
you make profit or not,
stock brokers, stock exchanges, government
and mutual fund houses, wealth management
companies always make profit because the
more your investment, the
more will be their cut and
we can see the profit of such companies continuously increasing.
All these companies are called
proxy companies of the stock market.  Out of which, the
IPO of ICICI Psalm AMC, which is an asset management company, has also come in the market
and one problem faced by IPO investors is
that they do
not get allotment because the issue size of IPO is
very small.
Even there, if a big issue is seen, the
retail quota is only 10%.
But in this IPO, there will be no
full allotment for retail investors.  Along with this,
we are getting to see a bonus thing in this IPO.
Where a shareholder quota of 5% is
also seen here.  So we will
understand the complete details of this IPO.
Understand the fundamentals and financials of the company.  Along with this, we will also understand its grey market
premium and reach the final decision
whether we should apply in this IPO
or avoid this IPO.
So overall,
watch the video completely from start to end.   If
you haven't liked the video yet, then
press the like button.  Let's go straight to
our video.  First of all, let us
understand the timeline of IPO.  Where
this IPO has already opened in the market on 12th December.
And
we can apply for this IPO till 16th December.   If
I talk about the allotment basis of the IPO,
it will be clear on 17th December
and this IPO will be
listed in the market on 19th December.  Ok?
Now if we talk about the issue size of the IPO, then the
issue size of the IPO is going to be Rs
10,602 crore.  Meaning, first of all,
we are seeing quite big IPO issues.
Where this total IPO which is going to happen is going to be
entirely an offer for sale.   This
means that the existing investors of the company are going to
sell their equity in this IPO.
Look, first of all, if we understand the
ownership structure of ICICI Psalm Asset Management Company, then the
ownership of ICICI Bank in this company is 51% and there is
a UK based company, Prudential
Corporation, its holding here is 49%.
So both the companies are going to
dilute their stake here to some extent.
Along with this, ICICI Bank is going to
buy back some stake.  So that
ICICI Bank can re-acquire the majority stake of 51%.
So now let us
understand the quota wise allocation of ICICI AMC properly.
First of all, the retail
quota that we are seeing here is a very
large quota.
Where the allocation for retail investors has been
kept at 33.25%.
Look, actually this retail
quota is 35%
in profitable companies but here it has been cut
so that the share holder quota can be fitted in this IPO.
Ok?  Earlier our
estimate was that we would see the total shareholder
quota being cut from QIB.
But actually there has been a
slight decrease in QIB here.  HAIs have
shown a slight decrease.  And here
we are seeing
your total shareholder quota of 5% by combining all three and retail.
Right now you can
see the retail quota here which is 33.25%.
Here we will talk about our reserve applications,
from which we will know
how many applications are actually going to be allotted in this IPO, we will
see that from the retail quota.  So this number we are seeing is
27 lakh.  Now you should understand this number very well.
27 lakh applications are to be
allotted here.  This number
tells us that if we see around 27 lakh
applications coming from the retail category in this IPO,
then all the applications will
get allotment.  Recently,
we saw an IPO of MSHO where 56
lakh applications were seen.  At present,
we do not generally see 56 lakh applications being received in every IPO.
Whenever a
strong GMP is seen in any IPO.  What
I mean to say is that GMP of 40-50% is
seen.  Where the demand is
very high.  About 55-56
lakh applications are received there.  But generally we are
seeing a trend of good IPOs.
In those good IPOs, we see applications worth around Rs 35 to
40 lakh.
But here in the case of ICICI Pashul AMC,
we are not even getting to see a bumper GM.
So for this, the
application number can be seen coming down a little here also.
So you can assume that around 50
lakh applications are received, which I am
saying is a very big number.  Still,
you will easily get one of the two allotments.
Overall, in the matrix of your allotment that will
come out, we will
see that approximately one out of half the
applications, that is, two out of three applications, will
easily get allotment in this IPO.
Also, if you
already have ICICI Bank shares
in your portfolio, you may have already taken them.
What I mean to say is that
if
you had taken the RHP on December 4 or before that, then
you are eligible to apply through shareholder quota.
Where
you can apply for two applications with one demat account i.e. one PAN card.
Where you
can apply for retail.  You
can also impose shareholder quota.  Or
you can also apply for Shareholder Quota Plus HAI.
We come to the next quota.
So here the next quota we
see is High Net Worth
Individual where generally a quota of 15% is kept.
But this quota has been reduced to
14.25%
and the remaining portion that we are seeing is
approximately
48 to 47% and that is the
quota of qualified institutional buyers.   If we
talk about the anchor book, the company has already raised Rs
322 crore from the anchor investors.  The
IPO has already been taken up.
Where
in the IPO of ICIC AMC, the remaining AMCs
like HDFC AMC, yours
means Axis AMC, all the
mutual fund AMCs have invested money which is a
very positive thing and
when anchor investors invest a huge amount then it is
a positive signal for any IPO
because whenever anchor investors
invest money then that money gets
locked in the market.  The
entire amount cannot be traded before 3 months.   This
means that whatever portion is
kept reserved for anchor investors, that
money is locked.  50% lock-in
opens after about 1 month and the remaining 50%
equity lock-in opens after about 3 months.  Let us
talk about the price band of this IPO.
So the company has kept the price band of the share at ₹261
to ₹2165.
Look,
I don't need to tell you much about the company's business.  One
company is an asset management company.  Where the
company provides mutual fund services.
Where
we can see about 143 mutual fund schemes.
Under their mutual fund business,
we can see debt equity funds.
Along with this, a lot of hybrid funds are also
seen here.  Along with this,
AF means Alternative Investment
Funds, PMS, Portfolio Management
Services and many other services
related to wealth management are provided by the company.
Talking about the growth of the wealth management sector in India, the
industry in India is growing at a
CAGR i.e. compounded annual growth
rate of about 14 to 15.5%.  This growth is considered
very good for any industry.
Now, if we actually
talk about the market share of ICIC AMC in this market, then in
terms of market share, if we
also talk about quarterly asset under management, then
in that sense the company
comes at second place.  Where
we can obviously see SBI Mutual Fund at the first position.
Whose market
share is seen to be 14.2% of SBI Mutual Fund.
Where their
quarterly asset under management is seen to be Rs 11.9 lakh
crore.
ICICI AMC is at the second position with a
market share of approximately 13% with Rs 10.9 lakh
crore quarterly assets under management.
Talking about the rest of the company's financials,
we have data from 2023 to 2025.
Along with this, we are also getting to see half yearly data.  First of all,
talking about revenue, in 2023 the company had a
revenue of Rs 2838 crore.
Growth was seen here in 204.  It had a revenue of around Rs 3761
crore and in 2025
it almost reached above Rs 5000 crore and if we
look at the half yearly data then it is
seen to be around Rs 3000 crore, from which
we understand that by 2026 we will
easily reach Rs 5000 crore, which
means if we talk about revenue wise overall then we will
see growth
because it is India's second largest wealth
management company, so we
can obviously say that brother the overall market is
growing, if the company will also grow then the
market will give strong valuations as well and if we
see in the last few times then
we have seen strong growth in all the companies related to wealth management.
Ok?  Now if we
come to PAT, PAT worth Rs 1515 crore was lost.
In 2024 it reached above Rs 2000 crore.
Reached above Rs 2600 crore in 2025.
And if I try to analyze these half yearly results, then
their PAT for one year is reaching above Rs 3200 crores.
Look, whatever I calculate the PE ratio,
I will do it only after taking the data of 2025.  So there
is no problem in that.  The rest of
their share price is around ₹2165,
according to which their market
capitalization will come out to be around ₹17000 crores.
This
is a slightly approximate figure.  Not a precise figure.
Ok?  So let us divide this.
So the price to earnings ratio that we are getting will come out to be
40.
Right now the PE ratio of 40 is
not cheap at all but I would
not call it expensive at all because the company
deserves this valuation
because we are
seeing the price turning ratio of HDFC AMC also of around 445, so
valuation wise, at present
we are seeing good valuation.
Now if we talk about its grey market
premium, then the
premium that you are seeing at the price of 2165,
but at the time when
I am making this video, the share is being seen at ₹192.  If
I go into percentage, I
see 9%.
Now understand one thing.  This premium of yours was
seen to be less.  But as soon as the
anchor book came, it came down from 6% to 9%.  Currently the premium is 9%,
so there is
no need to doubt this much.  The first thing is the asset
management company.  Where if the QIB
subscription gets blown out like this, then
instead of 9%, it can also be 15-20%.
I am talking about profit.  Ok?
So, where do we get allotment in IPOs
?  Allotment is not available in IPOs.
But when we see an IPO with 27 lakh reserved applications from the retail quota.  An
IPO of Rs 10,000 crore is expected.
Where our chances of allotment are
full.  So avoid such IPOs.
I am not feeling like it at all,
brother.  I will
go and apply for this IPO.  Ok?  And the good
thing is that brother, the IPO is coming from a sector
which is a very good sector and a
growing sector.  Ok?  Now
a problem arises whenever we
apply for IPO, the problem is that the
mandate does not come.  Mandates get cancelled.
You must have faced this issue many times
where you put a mandate.  The money got
blocked.  The application is not installed or the
application is installed.  The money is not blocked at all.
So there is a lot of problem with the mandate.
So for this it
is very important to launch IPO from a good platform.  So
I will put its link in the description.
I personally use the Dhan platform.
And brother, I am telling you this with an oath.
Those who use it, please
tell me in the comments.  At least
we do not see any problem regarding mandate here.   There
is a link in the description.  Go and join quickly.
Ok?  If you want to stay updated with the rest of the market
, if you want to stay updated with the IPO market, then
I have also put the link of SKKS
in the description.  If you haven't liked the rest of the video,
hit the like button.
I'll see you in the next new video.   Till then
bye-bye, Tata, Jai Hind, Jai